Donald M. Hunten Papers 1925-2011 (bulk 1946-2010)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Donald M. Hunten Papers 1925-2010 1946-2011
MS 578
Hunten, Donald M., 1925-2010
Donald M. Hunten Papers. The bulk of this collection consists of 25 notebooks. The majority are related to his career as an astronomical researcher at the University Saskatchewan, Kitt Peak Observatory and the University of Arizona.
9.35 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Donald M. Hunten was born in Montreal on March 1, 1925. He earned a Ph.D. from McGill University, Montreal in 1950. After earning his doctorate he became an assistant professor at the University Saskatchewan. In 1963 Hunten moved to Kitt Peak National Observatory where he joined the newly formed space research group lead by Joe Chamberlain.
In 1974 he moved to the LPL at the University of Arizona where he continued his research of the planetary atmosphere. In 1977 he became a professor of Planetary Sciences and eventually a Regents Professor at LPL.
Dr. Hunten received many honors during his career. In 1982 he was inducted into the National Academy of Science, He was awarded the Kuiper Prize of the Division Planetary Sciences of the American Astronomical Society and in 1998 he was honored with the Adam Fleming Medal of the American Geophysical Union (AGU).
Don Hunten was a major contributor to the unmanned space program. He was very involved in the planning and implementation of many of the NASA planetary missions including Pioneer, Venus, Voyager, Galileo and Cassini.
Dr. Donald M. Hunten retired from the University of Arizona in 2001 but remained scientifically productive through his retirement publishing single author papers in Nature and Icarus up until a couple of years before he died on December 14th, 2010
Arrangement
This collection is organized into eight series
Series I: Personal files,, 1982, 1995, 2005
Series II: Correspondence files, 1958-2001
Series III: Scholarship files, 1955-2002
Series IV: Grants and proposals, 1955-2002
Series V: Subject files, 1965-2003
Series VI: Photograph files, 1965-2003
Series VII: Dr. Hunten notebooks, 1946-1990
Series VIII: Digital Media: 1946-1990
Scope and Content Note
Donald M. Hunten Papers, 1818-2011 (bulk 1946-2010). The bulk of this collection consists of 25 notebooks. The majority are related to his career as an astronomical researcher at the University Saskatchewan, Kitt Peak Observatory and the University of Arizona. Other items in the collection are correspondence, photographs, computer disks and CD’s.
Gerard Peter Kuiper Papers, MS 480; Michael J. Drake Papers, MS 511; Charles P. Sonett Papers, MS 520; Tom Gehrels, MS 541.
Kitt Peak National Observatory.; University of Arizona-Department of Planetary Science-History.; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration-History.; Asteroids.; Solar system; Polarization.; Planetary Sciences-History.; Astronomy.; Jupiter; Nuclear magnetic.; Space Imagery.; Aurorae.
Container List
- Personal files, Series I
  - Birthday greetings, 1995; 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Congratulation notes /letters on Dr. Hunten’ election to the National Academy of Sciences, circa 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1958-2001.; Series 2
  Includes people and organizations (incoming and outgoing mail)
  - A, 1970-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Academic Press, 1969; 1977,; 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Akasofu, S.I., 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Atreya, S.K., 1978-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - B, 1964-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Barth, Charles A., 1960-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Baum, William, circa 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Belton, Michael J.S., 1966-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bertaux, J.L., 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Best, Gorden T., 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Blamont, Jacques E., 1958-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Briggs, Geoffrey, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Broadfoot, Lyle, 1966-1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Burns, Joseph, 1982-1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - C, 1971-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - C, 1971-1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carleton, N.P., 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Carlson, Herbert C., 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Carlson. R.W., circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Chamberlain, Joe W., 1959-1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Chamberlain, Joe W., 1976-1988; 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Chamberlain, Joe W., 1984-1985; 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Chandraiah, G., 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Chapman, Clark R., 1977; 1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cole, K.D., 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Coughlin, Bridget, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Currie, Balfour, 1964-1967; 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - D, 1972-1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Dachs, J., 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - de Imke, Pater, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Dickinson, Robert, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Donahue, Thomas M., 1966-1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Dressler, Alex, 1964-1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - DeMore, William B., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - E, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - E, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Elphinstone, Rob, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Eshleman, Von R., 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - F, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - F, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Fastie, William G., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Fink, Uwe, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fjeldbo, Gunnar, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Fite, Wade, 1976-1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fox, Jane Lee, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Frank, Lou, 1988-2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - G, 1978; 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gadsden, Michael, 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chandraiah, G., 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gehrels, Tom, 1981-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gerard, J.C., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Godson, W.L., 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Goody, Richard M., 1967-1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gross, Stanley H., 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - H, 1967-1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hansen, Jim, 1968-1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Hartle, Richard E., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hapke, Bruce, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hodges, Richard, Jr., 1976-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hunaerts, J., 1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Huntress, Wesley t. Jr., circa 1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - IP, W.-H., 1982-1983; 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - J, 1977; 1998 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Johnson, Terrence V., 1974-1980; 1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Jones, Alister V., 1960-1968 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Judge, Darrel L., 1969-1974; 1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - K, 1979; 1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Killen, Rosemary M., 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - L, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Landry, Bridget, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Linsky, Jeffrey, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Lellouch, Michael, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Llewellyne, Edward J., 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - M, 1969-1978 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Maran, Steve, 1976-1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Margolis, Jack S., 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - McElroy, Michael B., 1971-1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - McGrath, Melissa A., 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Morgan, Thomas, (The Lunar Atmosphere Review), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Morrison, David, 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Murray, Bruce, 1966; 1982 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - N, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - NASA, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Noxon, John, 1963-1987 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - O, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - P, 1973-1978; 1993 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Parker, Sybil P., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Parisat, Jean Paul, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Pepin, Robert, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Planetary Society, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - R, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Rundle, H.N., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Russell, C.T., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - S, 1976-1981; 1996, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sagan, Carl, 1972-1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Shemansky, Dan, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Slangery, T.G., 1997-1998; 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Stern, Alan, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Stone, Peter, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Strobel, Darrell F., 1973-1975; 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sykes, Mark V., 1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - T, 1973-1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Taylor, Fred W., 1975; 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Thomas, Gary E., 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Turco, Richard P., 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - V, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Veverka, Joseph, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Madjar-Vidjar, A., 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Visconti, G., 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - von Eshleman, R., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Zahn, U., 1972-1999 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - W, 1976-1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Walker, James C.G., 1967-1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Wofsy, Steven C., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Young, A.T., 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Yung, Yuk L., 1983-1994 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Yelle, Roger R., 1983-1994 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Z, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Zahnle, Kevin, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Unknown, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Scholarship files, 1946-1990.; Series 3
  This series is arranged chronologically and documents Dr. Hunten’s writing career
  - Subseries 1: Includes; articles, talks, lectures, presentations, etc., 1955-2002
    - A comparison of several systems for photometry of the twilight sodium emission, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - A Nomogram for solving spherical triangles, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Relative intensity of nitrogen band systems in Aurora, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - A Method of estimating albedo for dayglow measurements, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Interfernce filters, 1991; circa 1960, (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - A Cassegrain Echelle Spectrograph, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Sodium twilight at Christ Church New Zealand, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Excitation of N2 band systems in aurora, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Metallic emissions from the upper atmosphere, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Optics of the upper atmosphere, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - A Review of recent determinations of the composition and surface pressure of the atmosphere of Mars, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Excitation of the sodium emission in aura, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Comment on “Selection of low pass filters for shock tube instrumentation”, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - On Ejection of neutral hydrogen from the sun and the terrestrial consequences, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Quenching of metastable states of atomic and molecular oxygen and nitrogen, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - The Abundance and temperature of Co2 in the Martian atmosphere, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Emission in the twilight, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Upper atmospheric sodium and stratospheric warmings at highly latitudes, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Water vapor on Venus, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The Upper atmosphere of Venus: The regulus occultation reconsidered, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - The Abundance and temperature of C02 on Mars during the 1967 opposition, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Jupiter turbopause probe, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - An Estimate of the present day deep mantle degassing rate from data on the atmosphere of Venus (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Alkali emission (Aeronomy), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Martian dust storm: its depth on 25 November 1971, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - The Escape by light gases from planetary atmospheres, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - On Titan’s atmosphere and surface, (Planetary satellites colloquium), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Stratospheric pollution: How it dissipates, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Reshaping and stabilization of astronomical images, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Effect of the Jovian oblateness on Pioneer 10/11 radio occultation’s, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Performance of a silicon vidicon at low signal levels, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Slow scan system, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Image slicers, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Climate stability,(Conference on life in the universe,), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - New surprises from Uranus, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - The Jovian in region 0.4-1.1 um: The C/H Ratio, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Why send probes to Venus, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Capture of phobos and deimos by protoatmospheric drag, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - News from Moscow and Venus, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Detection of energetic Hydrogen molecules in Jupiter’s magnetosphere, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Thermal and nonthermal escape mechanisms for terrestrial bodies, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Venus: Funk and Wagnalls, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Theoretical astrophysics program seminar series, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - A Meteor-ablation model of the sodium and potassium layers, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Conversion of para and ortho hydrogen in Jovian plants, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Stability of Pluto’s atmosphere, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Transmission to space of the light produced by lightening in the clouds of Venus, circa 1982 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Recent progress in atomic escape, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - A Second order effect of Stratospheric vertical motions, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Planetary lighting: Earth, Jupiter and Venus, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Day and night models of the Venus thermosphere, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Nonthermal escape of hydrogen and deuterium form Venus and implications for loss of water, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - The Star tar in the Jupiter jar, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Blowoff of an atmosphere and possible application to 10, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Eddy diffusion coefficients in the mesosphere: Comment on “An observational study of water vapor in the mid-latitude mesosphere using ground based microwave techniques” by R.M. Bevilacqua et al., 1985 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Lighting on Saturn, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Moist convection and the abundance of Jupiter, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Dust trails, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Derivation of aerosol and sedimentation fluxes from published dates, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Theory of planetary atmospheres 2nd Edition, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Abundance of condensable species at planet cold traps: The Role of moist convection, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Kuiper Prize Lecture: Escape of atmospheres, ancient and modern, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - UVS calibrations and comparisons draft plan, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Titans thermosphere profile, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Early days of Pioneer Venus, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - The Sodium and potassium atmosphere of the moon and its interaction with the moon, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - The Thermal structure of the atmosphere of Titan, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - The Thermal structure of the atmosphere of Titan, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - A Possible meteor shower on the moon, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Galileo probe mass spectrometer experimenter, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Data collection with a portable computer, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - CO on Mars: Comment on a paper by Rosenqvist et al., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Venus: Lessons for earth, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Venus lighting pros and cons, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Notes on Martian oxygen and CO, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - The Equilibrium of atmospheric sodium, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Meridional transport and water reservoirs in southern Mars during, 1988-1989, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Atmosphere evolution of the terrestrial planets, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Atmosphere evolution of the terrestrial planets, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Line intensities in the 647.5-nm ammonia band at low temperatures determined intracavity laser spectroscopy, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Exospheres and planetary escape, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correction for dust opacity of Martian atmospheric water vapor abundance, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Clues to the Martian atmosphere, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Diurnal variation of Na and K at Mercury, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The Atmosphere of the moon since Apollo, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Nuclear magnetic moment of Scandium of mass, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Super – regenerative proton resonance magnetometer, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Evaporation of Jovian smog particles: A Source of hydrocarbons in the 10 bar region, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Equilibration of para and ortho hydrogen in the atmosphere of Jupiter, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Photoelectric spectroscopy, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 2: Book chapters, 1974-2002
    - Principles of astronomical Spectroscopy, 15th edition of the Britannica International Encyclopedia, 1974-1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Photoelectric spectroscopy, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Satellite, Astronomy, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Venus and Mercury,Encyclopedia Americana, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - The Atmospheres of 10 and other satellites, Satellites of Jupiter, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Encyclopedia of Science and technology encyclopedia, McGraw-Hill, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - IO chapter, Satellites”, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Venus atmosphere,Encyclopedia of the Solar System, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Venus planet, Microsoft Encata Encyclopedia, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Jupiter, The Century of Space Science, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Jupiter II draft, Composition and Chemistry, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Subseries 3: Conferences/meetings attended by Dr. Hunten. The majority have no papers., 1974-2002
    - The Upper atmospheric at the Jet Propulsion Lab (JPL), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - 27th Annual meeting Division for Planetary Sciences (DPS), Division of the American Astronomical Society, Mauna Lani, Hawaii, October 9-13, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - COSPAR meeting, Birminghan, Alabama, July 1996 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - The Three GALLILEOs the man, the spacecraft, the telescope, Padova, Italy, January 7-10, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Nates Symposium, May 1998 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - DPS 31st Annual Meeting, Padova, Italy, October, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Complex talk, November 1-5, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - DPS 2000 meeting, Pasadena (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Jupiter: Planet, Satellites and Magnetoshere, Boulder Colorado, June 24-30th, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Atmospheres of the terrestrial planets, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Grants and proposals with Dr. Huntens involvement:, 1969-2008.; Series 4
  This series is arranged alphabetically by organization,
  - JPL. Participation in the Galileo Mission, augmentation of contract no. 955026, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - NASA. Support for preparation of the book Venus, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - NASA. Terrestrial planets, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - NASA Observational studies of planetary atmosphere, 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - NASA. Theoretical studies of terrestrial planet atmosphere (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - NASA. In preparation for Messenger, discovery mission to Mercury, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Martian Water Vapor Studies, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - NASA. Hydrocarbons in Jupiter’s Troposphere, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - NSF. Imaging and spectroscopy of waves in the Jovian stratosphere, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - NSF. Planetary Aeronomy, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Proposal for the cloud particle experiment, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Final reports for federally funded projects, 1996-2003 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Lunar atmosphere telescope experiment (latex), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Series 5: Subjects, 1973-2003.
  This series is arranged alphabetically,
  - Europa Orbiter mission, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Geophysics and astrophysics monographs, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - John Adam Fleming medal (American Geophysical Union), circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory for Atmospheric and Space Physics (LASP), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Lateral flow (R. Yelle) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Preliminary study of a scattered light solar telescope for Kitt Peak by Jack Harvey, circa 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The Royal Society of Canada, circa 2003 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Space station, circa 1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Titan, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 150” Stellar Telescope – Blue Print, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 150” Stellar Telescope – Blue Print, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Book Reviews, 1973-1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Photographs, 1965
  - Untitled (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Mars Mariner photographs (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Photograph, Parkinson, T.D. (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Series VII: Donald M. Hunten’s notebooks:, 1818-1990
  These notebooks are mostly work related. There are some notebooks from the classes he attended while earning his degrees
  - Subseries 1 :Class notebooks before 1950.
    - 1. Nuclear moments. Book II, June 1948 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - P51 Lab., L. Ann Rubenstien, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Chemistry 452a, Research; April 1952-April 1953 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Electronics 1; Physics 255, Chemistry and Physics, 1946 (Box 7, Foler 4)
    - Physics 459-365, 1946; April 1953-June 1954 (Box 7, Foler 5)
    - Book III, 1953 (Box 7, Foler 6)
    - Untitled, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - L.B.S., G. Shepherd, 1954 (Box 7, Foler 8)
    - Rotational Temps, University of Saskatchewan, 1954 (Box 7, Foler 9)
    - Electronic computation, 1957 (Box 7, Foler 10)
    - Electronics II, 1957 (Box 7, Foler 11)
    - Aurorae Research VI, June 1954-July 1955 (Box 7, Foler 12)
    - Aurorae Research VII, July 1955-June 1957 (Box 7, Foler 13)
    - Aurorae Research VIII, 1957-September 1958 (Box 7, Foler 14)
    - Aurorae Research IX, September 1958-Febuary 1960 (Box 7, Foler 15)
    - Aurorae Research X, February 1960-March 1964 (Box 7, Foler 16)
    - General Research XI, April 1964 (Box 7, Foler 17)
    - Complex and SSB, September 1976-May 1977; April 1964 (Box 7, Foler 18)
    - NASA, 1976-July 1977 (Box 7, Foler 19)
    - SSB, SAC, SSEC, July 77; November 1977-April 1984, (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - SSB, SAC, SSEC, July 77; May 1984, (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Sodium records wedge photo meters, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Light sources, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Computations, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Digital Media:, 1984-1987, 2000, 2002; Series III
  - 3.5 Disks, 1947- 1990; Subseries 1
    - Ottawa radio flux including some executables for reading, plotting 3.5 disk, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Programs for digital signal processing and pkzip, pkuzip from Richard K, 3.5 disk, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Zurich Sunspot number 1989. See sunspot.doc. Includes some executables for plotting, etc., undated (Box 8, Box 3)
    - Job 13 disk 11, September 9-28, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Floppy disks, Subseries 2
    - CTM-05, UCCTM-05 UTILITY SOFWARE (1 OF 2) floppy disk, 1984-1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - CTM-05, UCCTM-05 UTILITY SOFWARE (2 OF 2) floppy disk, 1984-1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - CD’s, undated; Subseries 3
    - Comet D/Shoemaker-Levy 9 Collision with Jupiter; selected spacecraft and earth-based data. 6 CD’s (Box 8, Folder 7)